Email: sreedevagudi@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9591160066

Front End / UI Developer

"To do good work as a web developer & SharePoint Designer and to explore my professionalism in a company this can challenge my artistic skills."

Passion for designing User Interfaces; understanding a user scenarios, while designing a user flow; prolific; ability to manage multiple projects; creation of high quality concept graphics.

My experience includes core concept development and web site content management by using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JQuery, SharePoint Office365 UI Designer and SharePoint Designer 2007, 2010 and 2013.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMERY
5 years of Industry experience in providing User Interface & User Experience Design and Development with most usable enterprise wide applications. Specialized in full web site development, Front End Development and web application. Good Knowledge in SharePoint MasterPages, CEWP, CSWP, SEWP, PageLayouts, Responsive Websites, OOB issues, Browser compatibility issues, Parallax website and Responsive HTML email.

Analytical IT professional with financial expertise delivers strong technical solutions that solve business problems; always keeps an eye on bottom line business benefit. Offers a proven record of making outcome-based decisions that drive business process improvements and system-wide standardization. Build teams that take pride in developing high-quality, dependable systems and services.

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages/Scripts: HTML, XML, XSLT, JavaScript

Framework: Twitter Bootstrap, SCSS and Angular JS
Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, XML, XSLT, Parallax and JQuery

Operating Systems: Win XP, 7, 8 and 10

Testing: Functional Testing, Regression Testing, Integration Testing, System

Testing and Deployment Testing

Tools: O365/SharePoint Online Designer, SharePoint Designer 2007 and 2010,

Adobe Dreamweaver cs5.1, Adobe Photoshop cs5.1, Microsoft Visual Studio 2010 and 2013, Microsoft's FrontPage, Logi XML studio, Notepad++, Adobe Dreamweaver, Eclipse and Oracle Web Logic.

Database: MySQL

Version Controller: GIT, Tortoise SVN **Prototypes:** Microsoft Visio, Proto

Building/Testing Tools: Web Development Tool, Firebug, Color Picker, Page Ruler

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

B.Tech - Computer Science & Engineering

From 2005 – 2009 Sri Sai Institute Of Technology and Science, Rayachoty, Kadapa, Andhra Pradesh, India.

Honors & Awards

On The Spot Award

Capgemini,

January 2015

Received Capgemini STAR reward and "On the Spot Award" for solving some high and critical priority issues while working with 2 teams simultaneously. It was well appreciated by the customer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Capgemini

November 2013 - Till Date

Coxone



Coxone is an O365 app which is a SharePoint online environment. I am working as a SharePoint Online UI Designer, Created custom responsive MasterPages from Seattle and PageLayouts using bootstrap as per style guide and Irise Mockups provided by client. PageLayouts created first for mobile devices and later for desktops since we got different layout for desktop and Mobile devices using push/pull and flexbox. Good Knowledge in Configuring (CEWP/CSWP/SEWP) web part, worked in site settings and site contents.

Worked in site collection architecture, including use of content types and site columns. Design visual mockups; produce graphic assets and prototypes for quick buy off of user interface concepts. Develop content pages utilizing SharePoint features, HTML, CSS and JQuery. Build new Responsive master pages and page layouts to meet requirements and constraints. Test and validate solutions while actively communicating issues and risks. Configure workflows to automate business processes. Produce training materials and provide training to groups and individuals.

Environment: SharePoint Online 2013, Notepad++ and Visual Studio 2015

https://mod223137.sharepoint.com/sites/coxone

Monsanto



Monsanto is a SharePoint internal Troom-x project mainly for internal employees. I have worked for Creating custom Masterpage, PageLayouts and css based on style guide provided by client. PageLayouts created first for mobile devices and later for desktops since we got different layout for desktop and Mobile devices. Configuring web parts, worked in site settings and worked for web parts.

Environment: SharePoint Designer 2007 & 2010, Visual Studio 2010

AMINABOX



AMINABOX is a SharePoint internal project mainly for internal employees. Following tabs I worked in SharePoint designer, Due Diligence, Transition, Service Management, App Management/Development and CSI/Best Practices levels. Configuring custom master page, customizing layout, worked in OOB pages, provided Browser Compatibility support for various browsers, customizing Dashboard layout, configuring web parts, worked in site settings and worked for web parts.

Provided Access to various users like visitors. Created SharePoint search functionality in Home page. Added various customizations to the site and working for Web analytics to get the visitor users count and user details which will helpful to improve site.

Environment: SharePoint Designer 2007 & 2010

https://troom.capgemini.com/sites/AMINABOX/default.aspx

AOSMO Command Center



AO-SMO is an internal project managing Service Management Office for the accounts supported by Capgemini. The Command Center application is currently designed to support standard types of AM contractual and operational performance reporting for the accounts supported by Capgemini.

It delivers data in a presentable and accessible manner as web pages. It utilizes internet technologies and browser software to distribute rich, interactive reports and applications. The Command Center reporting tools bring leading-edge internet technologies together, allowing users to quickly access information efficiently.

The Command Center application can be used by any Capgemini employee and it is recommended that you use Internet Explorer 8 and above. The user can also access the application on Google Chrome, Firefox, cell phones, iPods and tablets that support HTML5 and above. With the data extract the application can pick-up data, organize data in the Dashboard, create reports Bar charts, Gauges, Tables, Analysis Grids with full enhancements. I have worked in Development Team, Transition Team and Run/Delivery Team.

Environment: Logi Info Studio Tool using XML, HTML, CSS and JQuery

http://imscc.cggm.capgeminiservices.com/IMSCCDashBoard

Infosys

April 2012 - November 2013

Develop UI design specs that allows and facilitate project and functional requirements across a multidisciplinary teams through all phases of the project. Design and conduct usability studies, translate user findings into affinity diagrams, event sequence diagrams and use cases. Generate UI mockups from wire-frame designs to high-fidelity prototypes that convey the interaction model. Designed intuitive and user-friendly interface and prototypes using (X) HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery and SharePoint designer for several.

PricewaterhouseCoopers



PwC is a SharePoint project which will mainly for internal employees where I worked. Following towers I worked, UCM(Unemployment Claims Management), TCI(Tax Credits), EI(Economic Incentives), PoH(Point of Hire) and AUP levels I worked in SharePoint designer and visual studio. Configuring custom master page, customizing layout, worked in OOB pages, customizing Dashboard layout for individual projects in each towers, configuring web parts, worked in site settings and worked for web parts.

And gave support to UAT and SAT while testing from offshore and onsite. And worked in dev and stage environment.

Environment: SharePoint Designer 2010, Visual Studio 2010 www.pwc.com

CISCO



My responsibilities to design prototype of customer data management layout and other pages including main page. All designs have to support browser compatibilities and table less design. Gave support for stage and dev environment for UI and functionality things.

Environment: Visual Studio 2008.

Adidas DMT



MY responsibilities to design prototype from search page to next results found pages and RMA search pages. Our WebPages will give cross-browser compatibility for IE (8, 9 and 10), Firefox, Safari and other modern browsers. And gave support from client reviews and from technical team.

Environment: Visual Studio 2010.



Telstra is an Australian telecommunications and media company, building and operating telecommunications networks and marketing voice, mobile, internet access and pay television products and services.

My Responsibilities for giving support to onsite and offshore environment while testing in ie7, 8 and 9. Firefox, chrome and Safari.

Environment: Dream Weaver.